Alex Poulos (PhD)

Hyattsville, MD | +1 (301) 437-4161 | alex@equul.us | github.com/mapoulos

SKILLS

I am a seasoned **cloud developer** with experience in multiple backend frameworks (TypeScript/Node.js, Java/Spring Boot, and Ruby/Rails) and cloud platforms (AWS and GCP). My experience includes writing and deploying both containerized apps on Kubernetes and ECS and serverless applications using CloudFormation and AWS Lambda. I love to tackle difficult problems; I excel at mentoring younger developers and in communicating with technical and business audiences.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

The Washington Post, Washington DC - Full Stack Engineer

July 2020 - Present (Full-Time)

- Product: Video Center, Arc Publishing's feature-rich video solution for videoon-demand and live streaming.
- Tech: TypeScript, Spring Boot, React and AngularJS, CloudFormation, MongoDB, Postgres, TypeScript, Broad range of AWS Services.

Equulus Consulting — Freelance Software Developer

June 2017 - PRESENT (Part-Time)

- Built, deployed and maintained a variety of small containerized and serverless applications in GCP and AWS.
- Tech: React, Vue.js, Ruby (Rails)/Postgres/ElasticSearch, Kubernetes (GKE), AWS Lambda, CloudFormation, R, Docker.

University of Maryland, College Park, MD - IT Engineer

July 2019 - July 2020 (Full-Time)

- Maintained and developed integrations for core enterprise IAM systems responsible for SSO (single-sign on) and RBAC (Role-based access).
- Tech: AWS (CloudFormation/Lambda/ECS), Docker, Java/Spring, Node.js, Oracle, Linux

EDUCATION

Catholic University of America — MA & PhD (Classical Literature)

August 2012 - May 2019, Washington, DC

North Carolina State University - BS (Computer Science)

August 2008 - May 2012, Washington, DC. Summa cum laude, valedictorian

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Solutions Architect, Associate (Dec. 2019 - Present)
Computer Science Senior Award for Achievement in the Humanities (2012)